起先 有了Daleks
First there were the Daleks...
然后 有了那个和他们抗争的人
And then there was a man who fought them.'
后来 他逝去了
And then,in time,he died.
当然 仍然有那么一群人 相信他活了下来
There are a few,of course,who believe this man somehow survived...
总有一天 他会再次出现
and that one day he will return.
亲爱的Hannah 为了我们
For both our sakes,dearest Hannah,
我们要相信这个故事是真的
we must hope these stories are true.
我收到了你的留言
I got your message.
很少有人能给我留言
Not many people can do that,send me messages.
我有个女儿 Hannah
I have a daughter. Hannah.
她被关进了Dalek的集中营 有人说你能帮忙 -是吗？
She's in a Dalek prison camp.They say you can help. Do they?
我希望他们别再这么说
I wish they'd stop.
选这个地方见面可不一般 -他们说我必须跟让你感兴趣
Helluva choice of meeting place.They said I'd have to intrigue you.
Skaro Dalek的起源星
Skaro. The original planet of the Daleks.
看看这里的样子
Look at the state of it.
谁和你提到我的 -这很重要么 -也许不
Who told you about me?Does it matter? Maybe not.
但是他们给你的信息很详细
But you're very well informed.
如果Hannah在Dalek集中营 那么告诉我 为什么你不在那儿
If Hannah's in a Dalek prison camp,tell me,why aren't you?
我逃出来了
I escaped.
没人能从那儿逃出来 你的手很冷
No,nobody escapes the Dalek camps. You're very cold.
有什么问题么
What's wrong?
这是个陷阱 -什么陷阱
It's a trap. What is?
你是个陷阱 而你却不知道
You are and you don't even know it.
博士已经被捕
The Doctor is acquired.
马上回来
I'll just be a minute.
呃 你丈夫在这里
Er...your husband is here.
我没有丈夫 -唔 显然你现在还有
I don't have a husband.Well,apparently you still do.
把这个签了
You have to sign these.
然后我们就离婚了 -变戏法一样简单
And then we're not married?Just like magic.
没时间和你聊天 我在工作呢 -真的 我以为你只是对着相机撅嘴呢
Can't chat. Working. Really? Thought you were just pouting at a camera.
Rory...
抱歉 亲爱的 我是不是打扰了什么
Sorry,love,was I interrupting?
天啊 看看你自己 很苍白 快过来坐下
Gosh look at you,you've gone so pale. Come on take a seat,
我们来打理打理
we'll soon sort that out.
Amelia Pond已经被捕
Amelia Pond is acquired.
多谢
Cheers.
Rory Williams已经被捕
Rory Williams is acquired.
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
好吧 现在情况有多糟
So how much trouble are we in?
有多糟 Pond先生
How much trouble,Mr Pond?
用十分制打分
Out of ten?
十一分
Eleven.
我们在哪 宇宙飞船 是吗
Where are we? Spaceship,right?
不是普通的飞船
Not just any spaceship.
是Dalek议会 别害怕
The Parliament of the Daleks.Be brave.
我们该做什么 -让他们记住你
What do we do?Make them remember you.
那么开始吧
Well come on then.
你们抓到我了 那还等什么
You've got me!What are you waiting for?
经过这么久的时间 你们该好好庆祝
At long last,it's Christmas!
我在这里
Here I am!
救救我们
Save us.
你会拯救我们
You will save us.
我会什么
I'll what?
你会拯救Dalek
You will save the Daleks.
拯救Dalek
Save the Daleks!
哇 这倒新鲜
Well! This is new!
第363天 恐怖的事情还在继续
Day 363. The terror continues.'
我又做了个蛋奶酥
Also,made another souffle.'
差不多吧
Very nearly.'
检查了下防御系统
Checked defences.'
他们昨晚又来了 总是在晚上
They came again last night. It's still always at night.'
也许他们是吸血鬼 噢 今天还是我妈妈的生日
'Maybe they're vampires. Oh,and it's my Mum's birthday.'
生日快乐 妈妈
'Happy birthday,Mum.'
我给你做了个蛋奶酥 不过它有点儿好看过头了
I did make you a souffle,but it was too beautiful to live.'
你会让我们进去 我们会进去的
You will let us enter!We will enter!
我们是Dalek 你会让我们进去
We are the Daleks,you will let us enter!
进入 进入 进入
Enter! ENTER! ENTER!
他在干嘛 -他在找这间大厅里最适合防御的位置
What's he doing? He's chosen the most defendable area in the room,
数清Dalek的数量 看看有多少出口
counted all the Daleks,counted all the exits and now he's calculating
现在他在精确计算我们之间的距离 他开始担心了
the exact distance we're standing apart and starting to worry.
哦 他开始皱眉毛了 Amy和Rory之间
Oh,and look at him frowning now."Something's wrong with
出了点儿问题 谁能解决这个
"Amy and Rory,and who's going to fix it?
然后他整了整自己的领结 -我们到了
- And he straightens his bow tie! - We have arrived.
到哪了
Arrived where?!
博士...首相要见你
Doctor...The Prime Minister will speak with you now.
你还记得你是谁么 在你被清除记忆
Do you remember who you were,before they emptied you out
变成他们的傀儡之前 -我的记忆只会在
and turned you into their puppet?My memories are only re-activated
他们需要进行深度伪装的时候被激活
if they are required to facilitate deep cover or disguise.
你有个女儿 -我知道 我读过我的文件
You had a daughter. I know. I've read my file.
哈
Well?
你对Dalek收容所有什么了解
What do you know of the Dalek Asylum?
根据传说 你们有个垃圾场
According to legend,you have a dumping ground.
一个你们用来关押出了问题的Dalek的监狱星球
A planet where you lock up all the Daleks that go wrong.
那些战损的 发疯的 那些连你都无法控制的
The battle-scarred,the insane.The ones even you can't control.
那对我毫无意义 -为什么
Which never made any sense to me...Why not?
因为你该杀了他们
Because you'd just kill them.
对我们而言 扑灭这神圣的仇恨是种玷污
It is offensive to us to extinguish such divine hatred.
玷污
Offensive?
Dalek也能欣赏美的概念 让你惊讶了吗
Does it surprise you to know the Daleks have a concept of beauty?
我以为你们已经没法让我不爽了 不过显然我低估你了
I thought you'd run out of ways to make me sick,but hello again.
你认为仇恨很美
You think hatred is beautiful?
也许这就是我们永远杀不死你的原因
Perhaps that is why we have never been able to kill you.
收容所
The Asylum.
它占据了整个星球 一直到地核
It occupies the entire planet.Right to the core.
那里关押了多少Dalek -没有统计数据
How many Daleks are in there? A count has not been made.
上百万 肯定有 -而且都还活着 -必须这样假设
Millions,certainly. All still alive? It has to be assumed.
收容所完全是自动的 不需要监督 -是武装的么
The Asylum is fully automated - supervision is not required. Armed?
Dalek永远处于武装状态 -什么颜色
The Daleks are always armed. What colour?
抱歉 没什么好问题可以问了
Sorry. There weren't any good questions left.
我们收到了来自收容所中心的讯号
This signal is being received from the very heart of the Asylum.
这是什么噪音 解释 需求解释
What is the noise? Explain! Explain!
是我 -什么 -是我
It's me. Sorry what?! It's me.
敲三角铁 好吧 我敲的声音不怎么突出 卡门
Playing the triangle. OK,I got buried in the mix. Carmen!
很棒的戏 有人在播放这个
Lovely show,someone's transmitting this.
你们有想过反追踪信号来 这些人谈一谈么
Have you considered tracking back the signal and talking to them?
我居然在问Dalek...有人么 有人么 卡门 有人么
He asked the Daleks...Hello? Hello,卡门? Hello?
你好 过来 过来 卡门 -你好 是的 有人
Hello? Come in,come in,come in,Carmen. Hello,yes,yes,
抱歉 你能听到我
sorry,do you read me?!
当然 清晰响亮
Yes,reading you loud and clear.
说明身份 告诉我们你在哪儿 -你好
Identify yourself and report your status. Hello!
你是真的
Are you real?
你是真的存在的
Are you actually,properly real?
当然 绝对真实的存在着
Yep,confirmed,actually properly real.
Oswin Oswald 初级娱乐部经理 这里是Alaska号星际飞船
Oswin Oswald,Junior Entertainment Manager,Starship Alaska.
现在的状况 坠毁在一个不怎么样的地方
Current status - crashed and shipwrecked somewhere...
已经一年了 剩下的全员失踪了
not nice. Been here a year,rest of the crew missing.
暂时还行 不过急需救援 -一年
Provisions good,but keen to move on. A year?
你还好么 你遇到攻击了么
Are you OK,are you...under attack?
一些当地生物 我一直堵着门呢
Some local life-forms,I've been keeping them out.
你知道那些是什么吗
Do you know what those life-forms are?
我知道有个Dalek 我听到了他们说的
I know a Dalek when I hear one,yeah.
你一个人做了什么才能抵御Dalek一整年啊
What have been doing,on your own,against the Daleks for a year?!
做蛋奶酥 -蛋奶酥 用来抵御Dalek
Making souffles. Souffles?! Against the Daleks?
你从哪儿来的牛奶 -这对话与情况无关
Where do you get the milk? This conversation is irrelevant.
不 这有关
No,it isn't!
不 嘿 你还在那儿吗
No,hello...hello!
因为有条星际航线坠毁在你们的收容所了 还有人进去了
Because a Starliner's crashed into your Asylum,and someone's got in.
而如果有人能进去 里头的东西就能出来
And if someone can get in,then everything can get out...
疯子Dalek大逆袭啊
a tsunami of insane Daleks.
你们也不想那样 -收容所必须被净化
Even you don't want that.The asylum must be cleansed.
那为什么这东西还在这里
Then why is it still here?
你有足够的火力去对付这飞船 把它炸到外太空去
You've got enough firepower on this ship,to blast it out of the sky.
我们无法通过收容所力场 -关掉力场
The Asylum force-field is impenetrable. Turn it off.
只有在收容所里面才能关掉
It can only be turned off from within the Asylum.
一个特遣小组就能溜进去
A small task force could sneak through a force-field,
派几个Dalek进去啊
send in a couple of Daleks.
哦
Oh!
哦 原来如此 真是棒极了
Oh,that's good.That's brilliant.
你们都害怕 不敢下去 你们都不愿意去
You're all too scared to go down there! Not one of you will go!
那么告诉我 Dalek在害怕的时候做什么
So tell me - what do the Daleks do when they're too scared?
我们会部署dalek猎杀者去执行 -你们没有这玩意儿
The predator of the Daleks will be deployed. You don't have a predator.
就算有 他们凭什么帮你们去关掉力场
And even if you did,why would they turn off a force-field for you?
因为你没办法逃掉 -请允许我做个说明...
Because you will have no other means of escape. May I clarify...
猎杀者是Dalek用来形容你的词汇 -我？我！
The Predator is the Daleks' word for you. Me?! Me?!
你们会需要这个
You will need this.
它可以保护你们不受纳米云的倾袭 -什么东西 纳米什么
It will protect you from the Nano-cloud. The what,the nano-what?
重力射线会送你们到
The gravity beam will convey you close to
距离力场发生器很近的地方
the source of the transmission.
你必须想办法关掉力场
You must find a way to deactivate t he force-field from there.
你们打算把我发射到一个星球上 这就是你们的计划
You're going to fire me at a planet? That's your plan?
我被发射到一个星球上 然后还要修复它
I get fired at a planet and expected to fix it?
说句公道话 这挺符合你的行为方式 -别替Dalek说公道话
In fairness,that is slightly your MO. Don't be fair to the Daleks
他们打算把我发射到一个星球上 话说你们要他们做什么
when they're firing me at a planet! What do you want with them?!
据称博士需要同伴
It is known that the Doctor requires companions.
哦 真天才 真好
Oh,Brilliant. Good-oh!
别担心 我保证我们能过这关 别害怕 -害怕？
Don't worry,we'll get through thisI promise. Don't be scared. Scared?
谁怕了
Who's scared?
开跳吧
Geronimo.
哇哦
Oi!
头朝下可不对
Wrong way up!Wrong way up!
Rory
RORY!
你还好吧
Hello?
你好 你是谁 你没事吧
Hello,who are you? Are you OK?
Rory 博士
Rory? Doctor?!
我叫Harvey 不是..
I'm Harvey. No...
谁是Rory
Who's Rory?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?!
嘿 哈
Hey! Huh?
抱歉抱歉 按错键了
Sorry,sorry!Pressed the wrong switch.
蛋奶酥姑娘 -叫我Oswin就好 既然那是我的名字
Souffle girl? Could always call me Oswin,seeing as that's my name.
你还好吧 -你怎么做到这个的
You OK? How are you doing that?
这可是Dalek技术
This is Dalek technology.
很容易黑进去
Well it's very easy to hack.
并不容易 你在哪儿 -船坠地的时候坏了
No,it isn't. Where are you?Ship broke up when it hit.
我猜大概是什么地下的地方 你来救我吗
Somewhere underground,I think.You coming to get me?
博士 -嘿
Doctor! Hey!
哦 蛋奶酥女孩 回来啊
Oi! Souffle girl! Come back.
Doctor Amy
Doctor! Amy!
Rory在哪儿
Where's Rory?
还有条射线 在那儿呢
There was another beam.There,over there.
你们是救援队吗
Are you the rescue team?!
嘿
Hello!
Rory
Rory?
Rory?!
RORY
RORY!
我们两天前下来的
We came down two days ago.
另外还有12个逃生舱
There is 12 other escape pods.
我不知道他们发生什么了
I don't know what happened to them.
Alaska号 和蛋奶酥女孩一样的飞船 -对
Alaska? That's the same ship as souffle girl. Yes...
但是她在这一年了
Except she's been here a year.
我们去那个洞里需要很长的绳索
We should have some climbing rope long enough for that hole.
不向大家介绍介绍我
Won't you introduce us to your crew?
哦 当然 伙计们 这是博士和Amy
Ah yeah,sorry. Guys,this is the Doctor and Amy.
伙计们
Guys?
哦 我的天呐
Oh,my God!
他们都死了 全部 -这不可能
They're dead. All of them.That's not possible.
我刚和他们说过话 就两个小时之前 我们在修复引擎
I just spoke to them. Two hours ago,we were doing engine repairs!
你确定吗 真的确定吗
You're sure about that,are you?
我倒觉得他们好像死了很久了
Cos I'd say they've all been dead for a very long time.
但是 但是他们不可能……
But...but they can't have been...
唔 他们不可能两个小时就变成骷髅 当然
Well,they didn't get in that state in two hours. Oh,of course!
我傻了 -当然 什么
Stupid me. Of course,what?
我死在了外面 有雪保存我的尸体呢
I died outside and the cold preserved my body.
我忘记我死掉了
I forgot about dying.
Amy 开门
Amy! The door!
解释 你擅长的解释 他们怎么都变成Dalek了
Explain! That's what you're good at.How did he get all Daleked?
因为他们都没戴这个
Because he wasn't wearing one of these.
哇 太聪明了 那个纳米云
Oh-hoho! That's clever! The nano-cloud.
自动处理所有有机体的微生物
Micro-organisms that automatically process any organic matter,
不管是死是活 转变成Dalek傀儡
living or dead,into a Dalek puppet.
一切攻击这个地方的东西
Anything attacks this place,
都自然而然的变成这里的保安
it automatically becomes part of the on-site security.
死的活的都这样 这些腕带保护了我们
Living or dead?These wrist-bands protect us.
这是唯一能阻止我们变成那个...
The only thing stopping us going exactly...
博士 闭嘴 无论死活 -是啊 活的 还有...
Doctor,SHUT up! Living or dead?! Yes,exactly,living,or,or...
死的 哦 天哪
dead. Oh,dear.
如果我怀念这种感觉是不是很糟糕 -当然 -感觉很好 -我明白
Is it bad that I've REALLY missed this? Yes. Good. I know.
未经授权者不得进入驾驶舱 -闭嘴
'Unauthorised personnel may not enter the cockpit.' Shut up!
哦 暴躁先生 坏东西 没点儿幽默感还有这么个下巴
Ooh Mr Grumpy! Bad combo!No sense of humour and that chin.
又是她对吧 蛋奶酥女孩
Is that her again - souffle girl?
我下巴有什么问题啊
What is wrong with my chin?!
小心点 亲爱的 你会戳瞎人眼的 我在扫描你呢
Careful,dear,you'll put someone'seye out. I'm scanning you.
你们在Alaska号另外的逃生舱里是吗 和我一样的飞船
You're on another of the escape pods from the Alaska,right?Same ship I was on.
你们在Alaska号的另一个逃生舱里 对吗
You're on another of the escape pods from the Alaska,right?
和我在同一条船上
Same ship I was on.
你是怎么黑进所有系统的 这太不可思议了
How can you hack into everything? Should be impossible.
你在一艘坠毁的飞船上
You're in a crashed ship!
说来话长
Long story.
有哪个词能来形容一个绝世的天才呢
Is there a word for total screaming genius,
不那么张扬 还带点性感
that sounds modest and a tiny bit sexy?
博士 你叫我博士
Doctor. You call me the Doctor.
我刚刚看到你的表现了
I see what you did there.
看一下地板 我在打通地板夹层的通道
Check the floor. I'm picking up a breach at floor level.
那里可能会有出路 待会儿见
There could be a way out. See you later!
啊哈 舱门
Aha,hatch!
看上去被谁使用过
Looks like it's been used already,
并在下去之后试图彻底关闭它
and they tried to block it off behind them.
用脚趾头想也知道为什么
Can't imagine why!
船舱的底部被埋起来了
The lower part of the pod is buried,
所以这里一定能直通收容所
so this must go straight down into the Asylum.
Rory在那里吗
Where Rory is?
说到Rory 你有什么要告诉我的
Speaking of Rory...Anything you want to tell me?
非得现在说吗
Are we going to do this now?!
发生了什么
What happened?
嗯 乱七八糟的事
Oh,stuff,you know.
我们分手了 你能做什么
We split up. What can you do?
我能做什么
What can I do?
你无能无力
Nothing.
这不像整整你的领结那么简单就能解决
It's not one of those things you can fix like you fix your bow tie.
别用那对水汪汪的大眼睛看着我 邋遢先生
Don't give me those big wet eyes,raggedy man.
这就是生活 人生无常
It's life. Just life.
你不在的时候就这么发生了
That thing that goes on when you're not there.
好吧 那么有人从这儿逃出去了
OK,so someone else got out this way then?
我们下去找他们吧
Let's go and find them.
哦 喂喂喂喂 他们到底想干什么 -那是什么
Oh,hello,hello,hello?What are they up to? What's that?
是这个 他们从哪儿拿到的
One of these. Where did they get it?
博士
Doctor!
他们从我手上拿的
They got it from me!
哦 Amy
Oh,Amy!
博士 没了那个我会怎么样
Doctor? What's going to happen to me?
说真的 告诉我 会发生什么
Seriously,tell me,what?
Sssh sssh
Sssh,sssh..
Ee-ee-ee-eex...
什么
What?
抱歉 你说什么
Sorry - what?
Eggzz,eggzz,eggzz,eggzz,eggzz.
蛋？你说这些吗？
Eggs? D'you mean those things?
Egggzzzzzzzz.
我不...我不知道你要什么 这些？
I don't...I don't know what you want. Those things?
这些是蛋吗
Are those things eggs?
这个
This?
你要这个
You want this?
系——
Eggggzzz...
奥——
term...
么——
in...
诶
ate.
系一奥么一诶
Eggzz...term...in...ate.
消...灭....
Ex...term...in...ate!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
紧急情况 紧急情况
Emergency! Emergency!
消灭 消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!Exterminate!
跑 后面有扇门 向那边跑
Run!The door at the end,run for it!
他们醒了但是动作很慢 后面的门 快跑
They're waking up but they're slow.the door at the end,just run.
快快快
Now,now,now!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminaaaaate!
Exterminate! Exterminate!
消灭 消灭
虽然是这个场合
So anyway.
我叫Oswin 我该怎么称呼你
I'm Oswin. What do I call you?
额...我想不起来了 额...Rory -很可爱的名字 Rory
Er...I can't even remember.Er...Rory. Lovely name,Rory.
我喜欢的第一个男孩的名字就叫Rory 好吧...
First boy I ever fancied was called Rory. OK...
事实上她叫Nina 当时我处在那个成长阶段
Actually,she was called Nina,I was going through a phase.
就是调情你来让你保持振作
Just flirting to keep you cheerful.
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
好吧...
OK...
任何时候你想再调戏我 我都没问题
Any time you want to start flirting again it's fine by me...
所以 告诉我 我会变成什么样
So,tell me. What's going to happen to me?
别撒谎 因为如果你向我撒谎我真的会砸到你身上
And don't lie,cos I know when you're lying to me and I will definitely fall on you.
空气中充满了微小的机器
The air all around is full of micro-machines,
分子大小的机器人 nanogenes（参见S1E09 The Empty Child）
robots the size of molecules,nanogenes.
现在你失去防护了 你在被...改造
Now that you're unprotected,you're being...re-written.
所以 会发生什么 我脑袋上面会伸出个杆状物吗
So,what happens? I get one of those things sticking out my head?
生理上的转变不会马上发生 -什么会先转变 会出现什么的症状
Physical changes come later.What comes first,how does it start?
你的意识
With your mind.
你的感知 你的记忆 我很抱歉 变化已经开始了
Your feelings,your memories and I'm sorry,but it's started already.
你怎么知道的 -因为这些问题你已经问过我四次了 -好吧
How do you know? Because we've had this conversation four times. OK.
现在我害怕了 -保持恐惧感 因为Dalek不会恐惧
Scared now. Hang on to scared.Scared isn't Dalek.
嘿 这里 碎碎念男孩
Hey there,beaky boy.
如果可以选的话 我更喜欢你喊我Nina
If it's a straight choice,I prefer Nina.
太帅了 你的鼻子 他的下巴 你们俩可以用脸比划剑术了
Loving this - the nose and the chin. You two could fence.
你后面有道门
There's a door behind you.
进去 快点
In there,quickly.
好的 你暂时安全了
OK,you're safe for now.
把衣服脱了 尽快 -为什么
Pop your shirt off,quick as you like. Why?!
一定要有理由吗
Does there have to be a reason?
那是什么
What's that?
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
看看别的地方
Keep a look-out.
别打开这扇门 Oswin Oswin 能听见吗
Don't open this door! Oswin?! Oswin,can you hear me?!
你好 长下巴 我有你的图像了 -为什么我没有你的图像
Hello,the Chin! I have visual on you! Why don't I have visual on you?
为什么我看不到你 -能源紧缺 发型糟糕 选一个吧
Why can't I ever see you? Limited power,bad hair,take your pick.
你左边有道门 打开它
There's a door to your left,open it.
我给你发张地图 显示在那个屏幕上
Going to send you a map to that screen.
我把你的小朋友救到安全的地方了
I've put your little friend somewhere safe,
我可以领你们去找他
I can get you to him.
Rory 你找到Rory了 -我叫他Nina
Rory? You've found Rory? I call him Nina.
因为个人原因 别问了
It's a personal thing - hush now.
你是谁 博士
Who are you...? Doctor...
现在我到底要对付多少个Dalek
How many Daleks directly ahead of me,right now?
10个 20个 有点难说
10,20,hard to say.
有几个神经兮兮的 但是都可以开火
Some of them are catatonic,but they do have firepower.
我怎么甩掉他们 Amy
How do I get past them? Amy!
小声点 没事的 他们只是人类
Shhh. It's OK. It's just people in here.
这只有人类 -Amy
It's just people. Amy.
是纳米云的作用 它在改变你的感知
It's the nano-cloud,it's altering your perception.
你再看看 看仔细了 他们不是人类
Look again,look again -those aren't people.
跟我过来 把手给我 跑 跑
Come with me,take my hand. Run,run!
看啊 他们下来了 -哦 是的 他们下来了
Look,they're coming down! Ah,yes,they are!
入侵者 -跑
Intruder! Run!
入侵者 入侵者
Intruder! Intruder!
它坏掉了
It's damaged...
是吗 那我们怎么办 -辨识我的身份 连接你的数据库 查找我是谁
OK,but what do we do? Identify me! Access your files,who am I?
来啊 谁才是老大
Come on,who's your Daddy?
你..是..猎杀者
You...are...the Predator.
读取你对猎杀者的指令
Access your standing orders concerning the Predator.
猎杀者必须被摧毁 -那你现在要怎么做呢
The Predator must be destroyed. And how are you going to do that?!
没有火力的Dalek 你就像屋顶上的三轮车
Dalek without a gun -you're a tricycle with a roof!
你怎么才能摧毁我呢
How are you going to destroy me?!
自毁模式开启
Self-destruct initiated.
它在干嘛
What's it doing?!
它要炸飞它自己 连带我们一起炸 它只剩这招了
It's going to blow itself up and us with it. Only weapon it's got left.
自毁模式不可撤销
Self-destruct cannot be countermanded.
我不是找撤销 小乖乖 我在找后退键
I'm not looking for a countermand,dear,I'm looking for reverse.
前..进 前..进 前..进 前..进
For..wards,For..wards,For..wards,For..wards!
Oswin 那是什么 离我很近啊
Oswin,what was that? That was close.
Oswin 怎么回事啊
Oswin?! What happened?!
谁杀了这些Dalek
Who killed all the Daleks?
你觉得是谁
Who do you think?
睡眠能帮助她吗 延缓转变进程
Will sleeping help her? Slow down the process?
就这么祈祷吧 因为很快
You'd better hope so. Because pretty soon,
她就会企图杀掉你
she's going to try and kill you.
Amy -哦
Amy. Ow.
Amy 你醒了 Amy 我在这呢 你还记得我吗
Amy,you're still with us. Amy,it's me,do you remember me?
她还记得我 -仍然是我们的Amy
She remembers me. Same old Amy.
你们知道怎么把一个人变成Dalek吗
Do you know how you make someone into a Dalek?
削减爱意 增添愤怒 她看上去好像太生你的气了点
Subtract love,add anger. Doesn't she seem a bit too angry to you?
看来有人从来没去过苏格兰
Well! Somebody's never been to Scotland.
那么你呢 Oswin 你怎么会没事的
What about you though,Oswin? How come you're OK?
为什么纳米云没能转变你
Why hasn't the nano-cloud converted you?
我说过我是天才吧 我躲起来了 -真聪明
I mentioned the genius thing,yeah? I'm shielded in here. Clever of you.
好吧 Dalek说这里是全自动的
Now this place - the Daleks said it was fully automated.
不过看起来都被破坏的差不多了
But look at it,it's a wreck.
嗯 因为我用了快一年来跟他们捣乱
Well,I've had nearly a year to mess with them
没别的娱乐项目
and not a lot else to do.
一个初级娱乐经理 躲在一个坠毁的船舱里
A junior entertainment manager,hiding out in a wrecked ship...
黑进全宇宙进化程度最高的
hacking the security systems of the most advanced warrior race
好战种族的安全系统里
the universe has ever seen.
但是你知道我最想不通你身上的哪一点吗 Oswin 是蛋奶酥
But you know what really gets me about you,Oswin? The souffles!
你从哪弄牛奶做蛋奶酥
Where do you get the milk for the souffles?
说真的 没人觉得奇怪吗 -不 坦白的说 真的不觉得
Seriously,is no one else wondering about that? No. Frankly,no. Twice.
博士 我查过你了 数据库里全是你的资料
So,Doctor,I've been looking you up. You're all over the Database.
Dalek为什么叫你猎杀者
Why do the Daleks call you the Predator?
我不是猎杀者 只是个有计划的人 -你有计划了
I'm not a predator,just a man with a plan. You've got a plan?
我们都听着呢
We're all ears.
有一个关于鼻子的笑话 有人想听吗
There's a nose joke going,if anyone wants to pick that one off!
排名不分先后 我们需要搞定收容所里所有的Dalek
In no particular order,we need to neutralise all the Daleks
把Oswin从逃生舱里救出来
in this asylum,rescue Oswin from the wreckage,
离开这个行星 以及 修复Rory和Amy的婚姻
escape from this planet,and fix Rory and Amy's marriage...
好吧 我数到 他说了三条不可能完成的任务 你们呢
OK,I'm counting three lost causes,anyone else?
Oswin 行星轨道上有一艘Dalek飞船
Oswin,there's a Dalek ship in orbit.
没错 我扫描到了 -收容所有一个力场
Yeah,got it on the sensors. The Asylum has a force-field.
上面的Dalek等着我把它关掉
The Daleks upstairs are waiting for me to turn it off.
一旦我成功了 他们就会把我们和这个行星一起炸掉
Soon as I do,they'll burn this world and us with it.
所以 Oswin 我的问题是 你用多少时间能把力场关掉
So,Oswin,my question is this. How fast can you drop the force-field?
非常快 但我干嘛要这么做
Pretty fast. But why would I?
因为这里有一个传送装置 对吗 Oswin -没错
Because this is a teleport,am I right,Oswin? Yeah.
只能在内部使用 但是我可以扩大它的作用范围
Internal use only. I can boost the power,though,
一旦力场被关掉了 我们就可以用它把我们
once the force-field is down,and we can use this to beam us
传送出这个行星
right off this planet.
但你说Dalek会在力场关闭的同时轰炸我们
But you said,when the force-field is down,the Daleks will blow us up.
我们必须快一点 -我们可以快一点 但我们要传送去哪里
We have to be quick. Fine,we'll be quick,but where do we beam to?
作用范围之内 只有Dalek飞船
The only place within range.The Dalek ship.
他们会当场消灭我们的
Where they exterminate us on the spot.
你这个计划只能让我们多活四秒种
This is the kind of escape plan where you survive four seconds longer?
四秒钟怎么了 四秒可以做很多事 Oswin
What's wrong with four seconds? You can do lots in four seconds. Oswin!
你多快能关闭力场 -我在这就能关
How fast can you drop the force-field? I can do it from here.
你过来我就关
As soon as you come and get me.
不 你就在那关了力场然后来找我们
No,just drop the force-field and come to us.
只有足够传送一次的能量
There's enough power in that teleport for one go.
你们为什么要等我 -为什么不呢 -不知道 我跟你又不熟
Why would you wait for me? Why wouldn't I? No idea,never met you.
给你发个地图 方便你来找我
Sending you a map so you can come get me.
这里到处都是Dalek -没错
This place is crawling with Daleks. Yeah.
所以我才急着想逃走 你们要是有时间就来救我
Kind of why I'm anxious to leave. Come up and see me some time.
那么 我们要去救她吗
So? Are we going to go get her?
是的 我们要去救她
I don't think that we have a choice.
好 力场一消失 Dalek就会进攻
OK,soon as the force-field is down,the Daleks will attack.
如果这里太火爆 你们就走 别管我 好么
If it getting too explody-wodyin here,you go without me,OK?
留你在这等死 -别担心
And leave you to die?Oh,don't worry about me
你才是要被传送到Dalek船上被消灭的
You're the one beaming up to a Dalek ship to get exterminated.
有道理 爱死这个计划了 Amy怎么办
Fair point,love this plan.What about Amy?
让她保持记忆 让她集中精力
Keep her remembering,keep her focussed,
那可以阻碍转化
that'll hold back the conversion.
那我做什么 -你听见她说的了 它们在削减你的爱
What do I do? You heard what she said. They're subtracting love.
别让它们得逞
Don't let them.
紧急情况 紧急情况
Emergency,emergency!
我们是Dalek 我们是Dalek 我们是Dalek
We are the Daleks! We are the Daleks! We are the Daleks...
好嘞 看着我 我是在逻辑分析
OK. Look at me.I'm going to be logical.
冷静又有逻辑 好么
Cold and logical,OK?
为了我们两个人好 你和我都好
For both of our sakes,for both of us,
我要摘掉我的腕带给你戴上 -为什么
I'm going to take this off my wrist and put it on yours. Why?
那会让你开始转化 并没有区别 -没错
It'll just start converting you,that's not better. Yeah.
但这能赢得时间 因为转化我的时间会更长
But it buys time.Because it'll take longer with me.
啥 -它会削减爱 她是这么说的
Sorry,what?! It subtracts love.That's what she said.
那又怎么样 你到底什么意思
What's that got to do with it?What does that even mean?!
简单的算数问题 转化我的时间会更长些
It's just arithmetic.It'll take longer with me,
因为我们都知道 我们一直都知道
because we both know,we've both always known...
Amy 我们关系的基本事实就是
Amy,basic fact of our relationship is that
我爱你胜过你爱我 在今天看来是个好事
I love you more than you love me.Which,today,is good news,
因为这也许能救我们两人的命
because it might just save both of our lives.
你怎么能这么说
How can you say that?
在盒子外 等你2000年
2,000 years,waiting for you,outside a box.
我只是说实话 而且你知道是实话 把手伸过来 Amy
Saying it because it's true,and since you know it's true,give me your arm...Amy!
你竟敢这么跟我说
Don't you dare say that to me.
你怎么敢 -Amy 你甩了我 -你想要孩子
Don't you ever dare! Amy,you kicked me out! You want kids!
你从小就想要孩子
You have always wanted kids,ever since you WERE a kid!
我却生不了
And I can't have them.
我知道
I know.
不管他们在Demons Run上对我做了什么 总之我无法给你孩子
Whatever they did to me at Demons Run,I can't ever give you children.
我不是甩了你
I didn't kick you out.
我只是放你走了
I gave you up.
Amy...我不知道...
Amy...I don't...
你还敢说在盒子外等我
Don't you dare talk to me about waiting outside a box,
这不算什么 Rory 跟对你放手相比
because that is nothing Rory,nothing...
这都不算什么 -把手伸过来 我给你戴上这个
compared to giving you up! Just give me your arm,let me put this on you.
不 离我远点 -把手伸过来 -别碰我
No get off me! Just give me your arm! DON'T TOUCH ME!
这是博士的 当你昏迷时 他一定...-时间领主
It's the Doctor's. When you were asleep,he must've...Time Lord.
还用说吗 他根本不需要这个
What's the betting he doesn't even need it.
那他怎么不告诉我们
Then why didn't he just tell us?
Oswin
Oswin?
我想我快到了 -没错
I think I'm close. You are.
20英尺以内
Less than 20 feet away.
这算是个好消息 -好吧
Which is the good news...OK.
我突然感觉坏消息也来临了
And the bad,which I suddenly feel is coming...
你即将通过特别护理区
You're about to pass through intensive care.
那么这又有什么特别的 -不知道
And what's so special about this lot then? Dunno.
特定战争的幸存者 在Spirodon星 Kembel星 Aridius星 Vulcan星
Survivors of particular wars.Spirodon. Kembel. Aridius. Vulcan.
和Exxilon星 听到过它们吗 -全部 -是吗 怎么回事
Exxilon. Ringing any bells? All of them. Yeah? How?
这些是从我手中幸存的Dalek
These are the Daleks who survived me.
博...
Doc...
士...
tor...
博...士...
Doc...tor...
博...士...博士...
Doc...tor...Doctor...
怪了
That's weird.
这几个通常怎么都不会苏醒
Those ones don't usually wake up for anything.
是啊 特殊访客
Yeah,well - special visitor.
有扇门 但打不开
OK,door,but it won't open.
不过离你应该不远了
You can't be far away though...
等等 也不一定 有个通行码 让我
Hang on,not quite sure -there's a release code,let me,
让我...那边发生了什么
let me just...Anything happening out there?
没 -别急 我在尝试
No. Hang on,I'm trying a thing.
博...士...
Doc...tor...
博...士...博...士...
Oswin 快开门 Oswin 快啊 -我打不开
Oswin,get this door open! Oswin open this door! I can't!
Oswin
Oswin!
拜托 把门打开
PLEASE,GET THIS DOOR OPEN!
博...士...博...士...
Doc...tor...
Oswin Oswin 拜托 快打开门
OSWIN! OSWIN!PLEASE,GET THIS DOOR OPEN!
救命
HELP ME!
博...士...博...士...
Doc...tor...Doc...tor...
哦 酷毙了
Oh,that is cool.
我酷吧 长下巴 -你做了什么
Tell me I'm cool,chin boy.What did you do?
稍等 我想我能开门了 -别 先告诉我你干了什么
Hang on,I think I've found the door thingie...No,tell me what you did!
Dalek它们拥有共享思维
The Daleks,they have a hive mind.
实际上也不是 但它们有心灵感应 -交流网 对
Well they don't,but they have a telepathic web. The Path Web,yes.
我黑了进去 彻底删除了
I hacked into it. Did a master delete on all the information
所有与博士有关的信息
connected with the Doctor.
你让他们把我忘了 -厉害吧 开门咯
You made them forget me? Good,eh? And here comes the door!
我试过黑他们的交流网 我都做不到
I've tried hacking the Path Web.Even I couldn't do it.
来拜见能做到这些的姑娘吧
Come and meet the girl who can.
嗨 你就在外面 快进来
Hey!You're right outside,come on in.
Oswin...我们遇到个问题 -才没呢
Oswin...we have a problem...No,we don't!
还没来得及介绍
Don't even say that.
加入Alaska号遨游宇宙
Joined the Alaska to see the universe,
却被困在飞船残骸中 这才是我第一次出去呢
ended up stuck in a shipwreck,first time out.
救我出去 长下巴 带我去看星星 -这些在你看来真实么
Rescue me,chin boy,and show me the stars. Does it look real to you?
什么看着真实 -你现在在哪 那里也真实么
Does what look real? Where you are right now. Does it seem real?
当然真实
It IS real.
这是个梦 Oswin 你为你自己编织的梦
It's a dream,Oswin.You dreamed it for yourself,
因为真相太可怕了 -我在哪
because the truth was too terrible.Where am I?
我在哪 我在哪
Where...am...I? Where...am...I?
因为 你是个Dalek
Because you are a Dalek.
我不是Dalek
I am not a Dalek!
I am NOT a Dalek!
我是人
I'm human.
飞船坠毁在这的时候 你还是人
You were human when you crashed here.
从救生舱爬出去的人 是你 那是你的绳梯
It was you who climbed out of the pod - that was your ladder.
我在哪 我在哪 我在哪 我…是人
Where am I? Where am I? Where am I? I'm...human...
不再是了 因为你是对的 你是个天才
Not any more. Because you're right,you're a genius.
而Dalek需要天才
And the Daleks need genius.
它们没有把你用作傀儡 它们对你进行了完整的转化
They didn't just make you a puppet,they did a full conversion.
我在哪 我在哪 我是谁 -Oswin 我真的很抱歉
Where am I? Where am I? Where am I?! Oswin,I am so sorry.
但是你是个Dalek 想想那牛奶 Oswin
But you are a Dalek. The milk,Oswin.
做蛋奶酥用的牛奶和鸡蛋
The milk and the eggs for the souffles,where,
你从哪弄到的它们 -鸡蛋 我 是人…
where did it all come from? Eggs. I'm...human...
我不是Dalek 我是人 我不是Dalek 我是人
I am not a Dalek...I am human,I am not Dalek. I am human!
鸡蛋 -那不是真的 那从来都不是真的
Eggs. It wasn't real. It was never real.
我是Dalek 我是Dalek
I am a Dalek! I am a Dalek!
消…
Eggs...
…灭
term...in...ate.
Oswin
Oswin?
消… 灭…
Eggs...term...in...ate.
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
不 不 不 Oswin Oswin 你听我说 Oswin 你不需要这样
No,no,no,Oswin,Oswin listen...Oswin! You don't have to do this!
消灭 消灭
EXTERMINATE! EXTERMINATE!
Oswin Oswin
Oswin! Oswin!
它们为什么恨你
Why do they hate you...
那么恨你
so much?
它们那么恨你 为什么
They hate you so much. Why?
我与他们战斗 一次又一次
I fought them. Many,many times.
在对你的恐惧中 我们越来越强
We have grown stronger in fear of you.
我知道
I know.
我试过去结束
I tried to stop.
那么跑吧 -你说什么
Then run. What did you say?
我已经把力场关闭了
I've taken down the force-field.
上空的Dalek要开始攻击了 跑吧
The Daleks above have begun their attack. Run!
Oswin 那你
Oswin? Are you...
我是Oswin Oswald 我与Dalek作战 我…
I am Oswin Oswald. I fought the Daleks. And I AM...
…是人类 记住我
human. Remember me.
谢谢你 -快跑
Thank you! Run!
跑吧 聪明男孩 然后记住…
Run,you clever boy and remember...
我们还能等多久
How long can we wait?
一辈子
The rest of our lives.
同意
Agreed!
好 走吧 快走吧 我们没事了 我们走吧
Right,go,let's go! We're good,let's go!
哦 看在上帝的份上
Oh,for God's sake!
收容所被摧毁了 有东西正从那星球传送过来
The Asylum is destroyed. Incoming teleport from Asylum planet.
我们正被袭击 准备防御 防御 防御
We are under attack. Prepare to defend! Defend! Defend!
解释 至尊Dalek
Explain,Dalek Supreme.
说真的 你们真应该想到这个
You know,you guys should really have seen this coming.
关于我 关于心电传送 我真的有个很好的目标
Thing about me and teleports,I've got a really good aim.
像针尖那么准 事实上 或者说
Pin-point accurate,in fact.Or to put it another way...
像吸盘一样
Suckers!
亮明你的身份 亮明 亮明 -是我啊
Identify yourself! Identify! Identify! Well,it's me!
你们认识我的 是博士啊 将要来到的风暴 猎杀者
You know me! The Doctor! The Oncoming Storm? The Predator?
这些头衔都没有意义 什么博士 -什么博士
Titles are not meaningful in this context. Doctor who? Doctor who?
什么博士? -喔Oswin 喔你让他们全都忘了 做得好啊
Doctor who? Oh,Oswin. Oh,you did it to them all! Oh,you beauty!
什么博士
DOCTOR WHO?
朋友们 你们得一直问下去了
Fellas - you're never going to stop asking.
哪个博士 哪个博士
DOCTOR WHO? DOCTOR WHO?
耶 -我能看见你 -好吧
Yes! I can see you! OK!
哪个博士
Doctor Who!
神秘博士
Doc-Tor-Who！
这艘船上有贵重货物
This ship contains the most precious cargo.
飞船将穿过大气层
The ship's coming through the atmosphere.
船上的生物不是用来买卖的
The creatures on board this ship are not objects to be sold or traded.
- 谁叫你来的   - 那是我爸爸
- Who sent you? - That's my dad.
- 发生了什么   - 有人登过这艘船
- What's going on? - This ship's been boarded before.
你认为我不会惩罚那些...妨碍我的人?
You think I won't punish those..who get in my way?
- 我在发射导弹   - 抱歉 你叫什么名字来着?
- I'm launching the missiles. - Sorry, what was your name again?
不管下面是什么东西 它正往这边过来
Whatever is down there is coming this way.
埃及的奈费尔提蒂王后
Queen Nefertiti of Egypt.
- 那是什么   - 恐龙! 在宇宙飞船上!
- What is it? - Dinosaurs! On a space ship!